Rômulo Soares

Tech Recruiter & Pshycologist - Linkedin

Santa Maria, RS, **Brazil** psicologoromulosoares@gmail.com

SKILLS

Has experience as a **Technical Recruiter**, conducting interviews with candidates and guiding them through the process until onboarding. Had daily contact with **English and Spanish**, working with people from around the world, from Ukraine to Argentina. Was the only Brazilian in the recruitment team, so was part of the Mexico team, and daily contact with different cultures was a norm.

The job involves filtering candidates who are fit for clients' software development projects, analyzing their proficiency level in English, technical skills, and hard and soft skills, and serving as a central point between candidate and company **from the beginning to the end of the process**. The requirements change according to the desired experience for the position. Among the tools that aid the process, mentions Zoho, Calendly, G Suite, and internal tools developed by the AgileEngine team to make the lives of technical recruiters easier. Interviews candidates daily who work with Java, QA/AQA, Javascript, PHP, .NET/C#, among others.

Also, is an experienced **Psychologist** and **Online Marketing Consultant** with a background in **digital marketing**, **content creation**, **paid advertising**, **and sales**. Since 2020, has focused on providing online marketing mentorship to psychologists seeking to attract more therapy clients, helping them to create their content, and how to market themselves. In 2021, expanded the practice to offer online therapy sessions, utilizing psychoanalysis principles.

Experience

AgileEngine, USA - Junior Tech Recruiter

April 2022 - March 2024

- Conducting preliminary interviews to assess skills, experience, and fit with the organizational culture.
- Identifying qualified talents through various channels, such as job boards, social media, and professional networks.
- Managing the full recruitment cycle, including scheduling and coordinating interviews, reference checks, and following up with candidates from start to finish.
- Providing regular updates and comprehensive reports on the progress of recruitment efforts and the status of candidate pipelines.
- Actively sourcing candidates on LinkedIn, reviewing profiles, and resumes.
- Communication entirely in Spanish and English, daily with the team.

Psychologist, Online

April 2021 - today

- Conduct online therapy sessions using psychoanalysis
- Provide personalized therapy to clients, addressing a range of psychological issues.
- Maintain strict confidentiality and ethical standards in therapy practice.
- Providing regular updates and comprehensive reports on the progress of recruitment efforts and the status of candidate pipelines.
- Helped numerous clients achieve personal growth and overcome challenges through therapy.

Online Marketing Consultant, - Sales and Digital Marketing

2019 - today

- Provide tailored online marketing consultation to psychologists aiming to attract more therapy clients.
- Develop and execute digital marketing campaigns, content and sales strategies, and paid advertising initiatives for clients.
- Educate psychologists on utilizing online platforms for client acquisition.
- Collaborate with psychologists to devise personalized marketing and sales strategies aligned with their target audience and objectives.
- Successfully assisted more than 200 psychologists in expanding their client base and enhancing their practices.

Education

Faculdade Integrada de Santa Maria, RS - Bachelor's degree in Psychology

Universidade Federal de Santa Maria, RS- Bachelor's degree in Special Education